Charles Augustus Lindbergh gift collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Charles Augustus Lindbergh gift collection
1927-1998
1927-1974
MS 325A
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
1.25
The collection consists of letters, photographs, and other materials relating to Charles A. Lindbergh. These materials are donations and/or acquisitions of discreet items.
Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974
General note
Yale University Library also houses the Charles A. Lindbergh Papers (MS 325). See IDCTYV84-A83.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of letters, photographs, and other materials relating to Charles A. Lindbergh. These materials are donations and/or acquisitions of discreet items.
Aeronautics; Lindbergh, Charles A. (Charles Augustus), 1902-1974
- Original accession
  - Correspondence
    - AML to Mary Ellen Chase, 1939, undated (Box 1)
    - CAL to J. L. McHugh and Stewart L. Udall concerning whaling throughout the world, 1966-74 (Box 1)
    - CAL to H. Robinson Shipherd and Yale University Library, 1948, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Memorabilia
    - Commemorative medallion of the CAL flight, New York to Paris, 1927 May 20-21 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbooks Volumes 1-4 [4 folders], 1927 (Box 2)
  - Map of New York to Paris flight, with annotations by Lindbergh, December 12, 1927 (Box 3)
  - Bound volume of newspaper clippings of Lindbergh's flight presented to him by New York Times, 1927 (Box 4)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-038
  - Architectural drawings and plans by architect, John Theodore Jacobsen, for the Charles A. and Anne Morrow Lindbergh home, "Argonauta," in Kipahulu on the Island of Maui, [photocopies], 1969-1970 (Box 1)
  - Dedication remarks at the addition of land to Haleakala National Park [due in part to the efforts of Charles Lindbergh; National Park Service has expressed interest in relocating Lindbergh home to park property; photocopy], 1998 (Box 1)